Contact

romiller@utmb.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/roger-miller-145750115 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare
Customer Service
Operating Room

Languages English

Certifications
C.N.O.R.
Nursing in Excellence Award

Roger Miller

R.N., M.S.N., C.N.O.R., Program Coordinator at The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston

Galveston, Texas

Summary

Program Coordinator for minimally invasive surgery.

Has managed vascular, transplant, general, robotics, gynecology, urology, and pediatric Surgeries. Experience in nursing includes Geriatric Rehab, Cardiac Cath Lab, Electrophysiology, S.I.C.U, N.I.C.U, Critical Wound, P.A.C.U and the Operating Room. Also trained as a Kidney preservationist.

Masters in Executive Leadership of Nursing, The University of Texas School of Nursing.

B.S.N., 2007, The University of Texas School of Nursing, Galveston, TX

A.D.N., 1993, San Jacinto College, Pasadena, TX Surgical Technology, 1989, San Jacinto College, Pasadena, TX

Currently C.N.O.R.

(2014) da Vinci Single-Site Training Program, Herman Hospital, Houston, TX

(2013) da Vinci Program Coordinator Training Program, Celebration, FL

(2010) Nursing in Excellence Award, Houston-Galveston Area.

Paratrooper, Member of the 82nd Airborne Division, United States Army, 1985-1988

Experience

UTMB

Program Coordinator May 2000 - Present (20 years 1 month) Galveston, Texas

- # Program Coordinator, Robotics, GYN, Urology, and Vascular services.
- # Operating room turn over efficiency leader.
- # Member of the M.I.S.(.Minimally Invasive Surgery) Committee

Page 1 of 3

- # Member of the Value Analysis Committee.
- # On the Professional Practice Council.
- # Works with MIS Administrative Coordinator on the new Jennie Sealy Block allocation.
- # C.N.O.R.

Houston Methodist Registered Nurse

August 1996 - April 2000 (3 years 9 months)

Large I.V. arterial management for post cardiac catherization.

I.V. sedation and airway management for electrophysiology and cardiac conversions.

Ben Taub General Hospital Registered Nurse August 1993 - July 1996 (3 years)

Trauma S.I.C.U., N.I.C.U., Critical Wound, and P.A.C.U.

San Jacinto College Surgical Technology Clinical Instructor 1991 - 1993 (2 years) United States

US Army Paratrooper August 1985 - July 1988 (3 years) United States

Education

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston Master's Degree, Executive Leadership (2016 - 2018)

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston
Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse (2005 - 2007)

San Jacinto Collage

Associate's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1990 - 1993)